

Shaikh Tahmidur Rahman

• Address: 35039 Marburg, Germany

Contract Phone: 015214165195

☑ E-Mail: rahmantah7@gmail.com

Website: http://www.devtahmid.github.io/portfolio in LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/stahmid

About Me

I am an expert in Backend Web Development and with my knowledge of building systems that interact with data, along with my strong analytical skills and programming expertise, my goal is to excel in the field of data science and tackle real-world challenges by making data-driven decisions. My enthusiasm for data science is driven by my passion for discovering meaningful patterns from complex data.

Education

04/2024 – present M.Sc Data Science

Philipps-Universität Marburg

09/2018 – 01/2023 **B.Sc. in Computer Science**

University of Bahrain

Focus Areas: Programming, Algorithms, Statistics, Linear algebra,

Machine learning, High performance computing

04/2016 – 04/2018 Senior Secondary School

The Indian School, Bahrain

Work Experience

03/2023 - 08/2023 Bahrain

Full Stack development (Freelance)

- *ChargeIt*: Car Charger Rental Application that connects charge port renters to 1000+ home chargers in 123 countries.
- *HealthMentor*: Application to help diagnose 19 mental disorders based on 52 symptoms, and recommend precautions and certified specialists.

07/2022 - 09/2023 Adliya, Bahrain

$Full\ Stack\ Developer\ (Internship)$

Truckly

- Built the Feedback System and Driver portal for a truck booking app of 1000+ users and reduced manual work by over 16 hours per week.
- Used DOM manipulation and AJAX calls to improve user experience and automate processes leading to increased efficiency of 77%.

Certifications

19/02/2023

Power BI Data Analyst Associate - Microsoft
Expertly trained in data connectivity, DAX, data visualizations, and collaboration in Power BI.

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services
Gained understanding of cloud architecture, data storage, and compute resources—integral skills for data engineers and analysts

Publications

01/2023 Real Estate in Blockchain

This thesis simulates the complete process of buying and selling property on the blockchain with the use of tokenized properties leading to efficiency

and security improvements.

12/2021 E-Government: Success International Cases

This research studies various e-government implementation, and suggests techniques to implement that can help mitigate failure factors and ensure

success of e-government projects.

Volunteering

06/2022 - Current Student Ambassador

Thinksmart

Coordinate course schedules for 25+ students every month and make sure

every student's journey is smooth sailing

Honours and Awards

5th place in Bahrain Kaggle Competition
 Bahrain University Association

 04/01/2023 2nd place in Senior project
 Awarded Second Place for Bachelor Thesis on 'Real Estate in Blockchain'

20/11/2021 Top 20 in Huawei ICT Challenge

Languages spoken

German (A1), English (fluent), Bangla (fluent), Hindi(good)

12-09-2024